Guide to the Philip Kapleau papers, 1952-2009 and undated RL.11661
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Recorded Teishos (Dharma Talks), 1975-2001 and undated; 3
  - B: Baso's "Very Mind" Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1975 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0063)
  - B: Kyogen's Moon Up a Tree Sesshin Day 6 Roshi Kapleau, 1976 October (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0034)
  - A: Roshi Kapleau Interview in Canada, 1979 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0001)
  - A: Dogen III - Buddhists Points to Watch in Buddhist Training; B: Day 3 - 5 day sesshin Roshi Kapleau, 1979 April (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0002)
  - A: Dogen III - Buddhist Points to Watch in Buddhist Training 5 day 3; B: Roshi Philip Kapleau, 1979 April (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0003)
  - 1: Rochester Zen Center Chanting Services; 2: Affirming Faith in Mind, 1979 May (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0004)
  - B: Selections from "The Practice of Zen," Hsu Yun, Hsing Tao, Ta Hui. Seshin Day 1 Roshi Kapleau, 1979 December (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0069)
  - 2: Faith, 2 Monks Roll Up Blinds Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1980 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0038)
  - Poetry of Rilke, Hanshan, Ryukan, 1980 July 29 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0005)
    Teisho by Toni Packer
  - Abbot Obora on Heart Sutra Sesshin Day I, 1980 August (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0006)
  - Abbot Obora on Heart Sutra Sesshin Day II, 1980 August (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0007)
  - Abbot Obora on Heart Sutra Sesshin Day III, 1980 August (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0008)
  - Abbot Obora on Heart Sutra Sesshin Day IV, 1980 August (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0009)
  - Abbot Obora on Heart Sutra Sesshin Day V, 1980 August (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0010)
  - 1: Three Jewels - Life of Buddha Sesshin Day 1 Roshi Kapleau; 2: 10 Items of Good Character from Various Points of View, 3 Resolutions, Roshi Kapleau, 1980 December (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0011)
  - A: Sesshin 1st Day; B: Roshi Philip Kapleau 3 Jewels - Life of Buddha, 1980 December (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0012)
  - Zen Master Bankei Sesshin Day 3, 1981 March (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0013)
  - Zen Master Bankei Sesshin Day 4, 1981 March (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0014)
  - Zen Master Bankei Sesshin Day 5, 1981 March (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0015)
  - Zen Master Joshu, 1981 March 22 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0016)
  - Disciplines of Thich Nhat Hanh The Precepts, 1981 May (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0017)
  - Disciplines of Thich Nhat Hanh The Precepts II, 1981 June (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0018)
  - Nansen's One Stemmed Flower also Thich Nhat Hanh, 1981 June 28 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0019)
  - Zen Master Ta Hui I Sesshin Day 3, 1981 June (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0020)
  - Zen Master Ta Hui II Sesshin Day 4, 1981 June (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0021)
  - Zen Master Ta Hui III Sesshin Day 5, 1981 June (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0022)
  - Letter from Bassui Sesshin Day 6, 1981 June (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0023)
  - Platform Sutra of Sixth Patriarch Sesshin Day 1, 1981 July (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0024)
  - Platform Sutra of Sixth Patriarch Sesshin Day 2, 1981 July (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0025)
  - Platform Sutra of Sixth Patriarch Sesshin Day 3, 1981 July (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0026)
  - Platform Sutra of Sixth Patriarch Sesshin Day 4, 1981 July (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0027)
  - The Precepts, 1981 July (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0028)
  - Teaching of Huang Po Sesshin Day 5, 1981 July (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0029)
  - Joshu's Newborn Baby Hitler, children, 1981 August 23 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0030)
  - Bodhidharma's Peace of Mind Sesshin Day 7, 1981 October (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0031)
  - 3 Resolutions, 3 Treasures, Precepts Jukai - First Precept, Roshi Kapleau, 1982 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0032)
  - 1: Dogen Shobogenzo-Zuimonki Sesshin Roshi Kapleau; 2: Tosatsu's 3 Barriers Day 6 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 April (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0033)
  - A: Hakuin - Orategama - Letter Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 October (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0034)
  - 1: Dogen Shobogenzo Zuimonki I Roshi Kapleau; 2: Tosatsu's 3 Barriers Sesshin Day 6 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0035)
  - 1: 3 Letters Tempyo's 2 Mistakes Roshi Kapleau, 1982 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0036)
  - 1: 3 letters "Tempyo's 2 Mistakes", 1982 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0037)
  - 1: It Will Go Along With All the Rest Roshi Kapleau, 1982 May (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0038)
  - Bodhidharma and Mind Pacifying, 1982 October (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0039)
  - 1: The Diamond Sutra and Being Reviled - Also Comments on Nuclear War Roshi Kapleau; 2 Dogo's "I Won't Say," Also Koan Study Roshi Kapleau, 1982 May (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0040)
  - The Diamond Sutra and Being Reviled - Also Comments on Nuclear War Roshi Kapleau, 1982 May (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0041)
  - A: Joshu Sees Through Old Woman Sesshin Day 6 Koestler, 1982 May (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0042)
  - 1: Hui Hai I Sesshin Day 1; 2: Hui Hai II Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0043)
  - 1: Hui Hai I; 2: Hui Hai II Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0044)
  - Introduction to Koans and Mumonkan "Kicking Over Water Bottle" Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0045)
  - What is Kensho - Post Kensho Practice - 2nd and 3rd precepts Roshi Kapleau, 1982 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0046)
  - 2: Joshu and Two Hermits, Talk on Freedom and Independence, 1982 July 4 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0066)
  - B: Dogen - Shobogenzo IV "Causality", 1982 November (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0096)
  - 1: Hakuin - Orotogama - Letter Part 3 Sesshin Day 3; 2: Hakuin - Orategama - Letter Part 4 Sesshin Day 4 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 October (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0047)
  - 1: Step Forward from the Top of 100 Foot Pole Sesshin Day 7 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 November (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0048)
  - Step Forward from the Top of 100 Foot Pole Sesshin Day 7 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 November (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0049)
  - 1: Life of the Buddha I Sesshin Day 1; 2: Life of the Buddha II Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0050)
  - 1: Life of the Buddha I Sesshin Day 1; 2: Life of the Buddha II Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1982 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0051)
  - 2: Help in Zen Nixon Roshi Kapleau, 1983 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0048)
  - A: Po Shan Sesshin Day 4, 1982 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0052)
  - 1: Po Shan Sesshin Day 4 Roshi Kapleau; 2: Buddha Holds Up a Flower Roshi Kapleau, 1982 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0053)
  - 1: Basui II Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0054)
  - B: Joshu and 2 Hermits Sesshin Day 3, 1983 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0065)
  - 2: Nansen Kills the Cat Sesshn Day 6 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0037)
  - No Mindedness, Anger, Modern Physics Roshi Kapleau, 1983 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0055)
  - No Mindedness, Anger, Modern Physics Roshi Kapleau, 1983 April (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0056)
  - Various Letter Buddhist Compassion Roshi Kapleau, 1983 May (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0057)
  - 1: Hakuin Yabukoji I Sesshin Day 1; 2: Hakuin Yabukoji II Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 May (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0058)
  - Ordinary Mind Sesshin Day 4 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 May (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0059)
  - 1: Huang Po I Sesshin Day 1; 2: Huang Po II Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0060)
  - Huang Po III Sesshin Day 3, 1983 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0061)
  - Huan Po IV Sesshin Day 4 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0062)
  - B: Talk by Monk of 3rd Seat Sesshin Day 5, 1983 June (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0042)
  - A: Buddhist Compassion and Political Involvement Roshi Kapleau, 1983 October (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0063)
  - B: Buddha Holds Up a Flower Sesshin Day 6, 1983 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0052)
  - A: Hyakujo and the Fox Sesshin Day 6; B: Kyogen - Man/Tree Roshi Kapleau, 1983 October (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0064)
  - A: Thinking Neither Good Nor Evil Sesshin Day 7 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 October (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0065)
  - 1: Practice of Zen (Hsu Vun) Sesshin Day 1, 1983 November (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0066)
  - Myth and Mysticism Roshi Kapleau, 1983 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0067)
  - 1: Han Shan I Sesshin Day 3; 2: Han Shan II Sesshin Day 4 Roshi Philip Kapleau, 1983 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0068)
  - A: A Non-Buddhist Questions the Buddha Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1983 December (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0069)
  - 2: Mu Sesshin Day 7, 1983 December (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0054)
  - Letters, Culture, Technology Roshi Kapleau, 1984 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0070)
  - Response to Letter on Loneliness, 1984 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0071)
    Talk by Toni Packer, Genesee Valley Zen Center
  - Hakuin - Orategama I Sesshin Day 1, 1984 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0072)
  - Nansen's Cat - Easter Roshi Kapleau, 1984 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0073)
  - Oxherding Pictures I Roshi Kapleau, 1984 June 3 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0074)
  - A: Oxherding Pictures II Sesshin Day 1 Roshi Kapleau, 1984 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0075)
  - B: Ryutan Blows Out a Candle, 1983 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0075)
  - 1: Ta Hui Letters and Lectures I Sesshin Day 2; 2: Ta Hui Letters and Lectures II Sesshin Day 3 Roshi Kapleau, 1984 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0076)
  - A: Ta Hui Letters and Lectures Sesshin Day 2; B: Ta Hui II Sesshin Day 3 Roshi Kapleau, 1984 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0077)
  - Concentration and Awareness Sesshin Day 3, 1984 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0078)
  - A: Joshu's Shirt Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1984 November (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0079)
  - Precepts Roshi Kapleau, 1985 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0080)
  - Einstein, Shanti-Deva Roshi Kapleau, 1985 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0081)
  - A: Tozan Sesshin Day 7; B: Takosan Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1985 May (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0082)
  - B: Practice of Zen - Chang Sesshin Day 2 Roshi Kapleau, 1985 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0086)
  - Tozan's No Cold No Hot, 1985 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0083)
  - Dokusan Roshi, 1985 October (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0084)
  - A: On Harada Roshi on Buffalo Passing Through Window Sesshin Day 5; B: Yasutani Roshi on Mu Sesshin Day 7 Roshi Kapleau, 1985 December (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0085)
  - B: Shakyamuni Holds Up a Flower Sesshin Day 6 Roshi Kapleau, 1985 December (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0080)
  - A: Life of the Buddha, 1985 December 2 (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0086)
  - B: Collected Works of Chinul Roshi Kapleau, 1986 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0094)
  - Letters, Articles, "Soft Answer", 1986 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0087)
  - Shobogenzo Zuimonki II Sensei Bodhin, 1986 April (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0088)
  - A: Zuigan Calls the Master Sesshin Day 4; B: Tokusan Carries His Bowls Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1986 May (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0089)
  - A: Bodhidharma's "I Don't Know" Treatise on Contemplating Mind; Tokusan Carries His Bundle, 1986 May (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0090)
  - B: Hui-Neng and the Platform Sutra Sesshin Day 1 Roshi Kapleau, 1986 May (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0091)
  - A: Kempo's One Way Sesshin Roshi Kapleau, 1986 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0091)
  - A: Totatsu's 3 Barriers Sesshin Day 6; B: Shizan Raises His Staff Sesshin Day 5 Roshi Kapleau, 1986 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0092)
  - Transplanting Zen to America Bodhin Sensei, 1986 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0093)
  - A: Relaxation; Letter from John Blofeld, Roshi's Thoughts on Experience in Hospital, 1986 October (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0094)
  - A: Precepts 1986 I; B: Ta Hui I Roshi Kapleau, 1986 November, December (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0095)
  - A: Ummon's Everyday is a Good Day, 1986 December (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0096)
  - A: Way of Korean Zen II Bodhin; B: Sutra of Sixth Patriarch Bodhin, 1987 February, June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0097)
  - Zen and Psychotherapy Sensei Bodhin, 1987 June (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0098)
  - B: Transgression is Wiped Out Kapleau, 1987 July (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0079)
  - A: Issan Kicks the Water Bottle; B: Ketchu's Carts Roshi Kapleau, 1987 December (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0099)
  - Precepts I Bodhin Sensei, 1988 January (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0100)
  - Precepts II Sensei Kjolhede, 1988 January (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0101)
  - Precepts III Bodhin Sensei, 1988 January (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0102)
  - Life of Buddha Roshi Kapleau, 1988 January (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0103)
  - Life of Buddha II Roshi Kapleau, 1988 January (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0104)
  - Autobiography of Harada Roshi Roshi Kapleau, 1988 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0105)
  - The Man Who Mistook His Wife for a Hat Bodhin, 1988 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0106)
  - Purpose and Spirit of Dokusan Sesshin Day 3 Bodhin Sensei, 1988 April (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0107)
  - Letters of Ta-Hui I Roshi Kapleau, 1989 March (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0108)
  - Letters of Ta-Hui II Roshi Kapleau, 1989 March (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0109)
  - Tun Huang Caves I Roshi Kapleau, 1989 March (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0110)
  - Tun Huang Caves II Roshi Kapleau, 1989 March (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0111)
  - Chinul I Bodhin Sensei, 1989 April (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0112)
  - Chinul II Bodhin Sensei, 1989 April (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0113)
  - Chinul III Bodhin Sensei, 1989 April (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0114)
  - Ryuge Asks Suibi and Rinzai Bodhin Sensei, 1989 April (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0115)
  - Biography Harada Roshi I Roshi Kapleau, 1989 June (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0116)
  - Biography of Harada Roshi II Roshi Kapleau, 1989 June (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0117)
  - Tangen Roshi, Roshi Kapleau, 1989 June (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0118)
  - Tangen Roshi II Roshi Kapleau, 1989 June (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0119)
  - Tokusan Carries His Bowls, 1989 June (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0120)
  - Think Neither Good Nor Evil Roshi Kapleau, 1989 June (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0121)
  - Gensha's Man of Three Disabilities Roshi Kapleau, 1989 June (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0122)
  - Talks of Bassui I, "Mud and Water" Sensei, 1989 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0123)
  - Talks of Bassui II Sensei, 1989 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0124)
  - Talks of Bassui IV Sensei, 1989 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0125)
  - Talks of Bassui V Sensei, 1989 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0126)
  - The Life of the Buddha Sensei, 1989 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0127)
  - Commentary on the Poem "Flowers" Sensei, 1989 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0128)
  - A: Bassui I; B: Commentary on "Flowers" Bodhin Sensei, 1989 December (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0129)
  - The World as Sound and Music (Nada Brahma) Bodhin Sensei, 1990 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0130)
  - Zen Chanting, 1990 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0131)
  - Zen Teaching of Hui-Hai I Roshi, 1990 August (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0132)
  - Zen Teaching of Hui-Hai II Roshi, 1990 August (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0133)
  - Zen Teaching of Hui-Hai III Roshi, 1990 August (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0134)
  - No Cold or Heat Roshi, 1990 August (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0135)
  - Ramana Maharshi I, 1991 April (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0136)
  - Ramana Maharshi II, 1991 April (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0137)
  - Ramana Maharshi III, 1991 April (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0138)
  - Zibo The Last Great Chinese Zen Master, 1991 July (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0139)
  - Zibo II, 1991 July (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0140)
  - Zibo III, 1991 July (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0141)
  - Zibo IV, 1991 July (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0142)
  - The Practice of Zen C. C. Chang, 1991 July (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0143)
  - Kicking Over the Water Bottle, 1991 July (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0144)
  - Yakusan's King of the Deer, 1991 July (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0145)
  - A: Roshi Speaks About His Illness; B: Enlightenment, 1991 November (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0146)
  - Faith, Doubt, and Determination I, 1992 January (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0147)
  - Faith, Doubt, and Determination II, 1992 January (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0148)
  - Roshi Philip Kapleau Comments on Easter and Passover then Koan, 1992 March 12 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0149)
  - Medicine and Sickness Cure Disease Unmon, 1992 April 5 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0150)
  - The Problem of Racial Violence in America Roshi Kapleau, 1992 May 10 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0151)
  - Hollywood, FL Roshi Kapleau, 1992 November, December (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0152)
  - A: The Relation of Physic and Mysticism; B: Fragment of an Article by Terry Dobson "A Soft Answer" and commentaries on Ch'an Master Sheng-yen, 1992 October, December (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0153)
  - Roshi in Atlanta, 1993 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0154)
  - Significance of Buddha's Life and Enlightenment Vesak, 1993 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0155)
  - A: Letter on Sangha and Assorted Articles; B: Preventing War Roshi Kapleau, 1993 March 21 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0156)
  - Desire, 1993 May 23 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0157)
  - Kyasei's Sound of the Raindrops, 1993 June 5 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0158)
  - Kyogen's Man Up a Tree, 1993 June 6 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0159)
  - Abandon Word and Silence, 1993 June 7 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0160)
  - American Problems with Zen and Kensho II, 1994 July 10 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0161)
  - An Experience of Enlightenment Flora Courtois I Sonja Sensei, 1994 December (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0162)
  - An Experience of Enlightenment Flora Courtois II Sonja Sensei, 1994 December (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0163)
  - An Experience of Enlightenment Flora Courtois III Sonya Sensei, 1994 December (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0164)
  - Zen Teaching of Huang Po, 1994 December (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0165)
  - Roshi and his Teachers, Dharma Transmission and the Rochester Zen Center Lineage, 1995 January 8 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0166)
  - Dharma Talk Jim Bedard, 1995 November 16 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0167)
  - Mud and Water - Bassui I, 1996 April (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0168)
  - Mud and Water - Bassui II, 1996 April (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0169)
  - Mud and Water - Bassui III, 1996 April (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0170)
  - Mud and Water - Bassui IV, 1996 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0171)
  - Mud and Water - Bassui V, 1996 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0172)
  - Enkan and the Rhinoceros Horn Fan, 1996 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0173)
  - Chang-sha Goes for a Walk, 1996 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0174)
  - Swampland Flowers Ta-Hui I, 1996 July (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0175)
  - Swampland Flowers Ta-Hui II, 1996 July (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0176)
  - Swampland Flowers Ta-Hui III, 1996 July (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0177)
  - Swampland Flowers Ta-Hui IV, 1996 July (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0178)
  - Swampland Flowers Ta-Hui V, 1996 July (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0179)
  - Myoko Goes to Shobei, 1996 July (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0180)
  - Bodhisattva Fu Lectures on the Diamond Sutra, 1996 July (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0181)
  - Life of Zen Master Dogen, 1996 October (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0182)
  - Chaos, Order and Chapin Mill, 2000 September 17 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0183)
  - Sudden Illumination Hui-Hai I, 2001 February (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0184)
  - Sudden Illumination Hui-Hai II, 2001 February (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0185)
  - The Way of Korean Zen Kusan Sunim I, 2001 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0186)
  - The Way of Korean Zen Kusan Sunim II, 2001 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0187)
  - The Way of Korean Zen Kusan Sunim III, 2001 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0188)
  - The Way of Korean Zen Kusan Sunim IV, 2001 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0189)
  - The Way of Korean Zen Kusan Sunim V, 2001 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0190)
  - The Way of Korean Zen Kusan Sunim VI, 2001 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0191)
  - Nansen Cuts the Cat in Two, 2001 April (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0192)
  - Dharmasala II, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0193)
  - Dharmasala II, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0194)
  - A: Nansen's Ordinary Mind; B: Tosatsu's 3 Barriers Danan Sensei, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0195)
  - A: Dogo's "I Won't Tell You" Koan Train; B: Reading and Commentary on Articles and Letters, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0196)
  - A: Dogo's "I Won't Say" Day of Dead; B: Cosmic Buddha Way II, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0197)
  - Ten Items of Good Character from Various Points of View - Three Resolutions Roshi Kapleau, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0198)
  - Zen Master Zibo Bodhin Sensai, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0199)
  - A: Zibo II; B: Zibo III Sensai, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0200)
  - Facing Death Bodhin Sensai, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL11661-CS-0201)
  - Roshi - Chelation, undated (Box 15, Audio-reel RL11661-RR-0001)